## Carla M. Rodrigues

173 Kingsbury Court • Nazareth, PA 18064 570-856-4226 • cmr9532@gmail.com www.MrsCarlaRodrigues.com

## **PROFILE**

I am a self-motivated and passionate teacher that combines diverse experiences, talents and special skills to create a nurturing and enthusiastic learning environment for children. I believe that every child is capable of learning when motivation, meaning, creativity, and exploration are embedded in daily lessons and activities, which are designed to also extend children's knowledge and fulfill their full potential.

## CERTIFICATION

PA Teaching Certificate in Elementary Education (K-6) PA Teaching Certificate in Special Education (N-12)

## EXPERIENCE

# F.A. March Elementary School, Easton Area School District, Easton, PA 2009-present Second Grade Teacher

- Design and implement lessons aligned with the PA Common Core Standards for Language Arts, Math, Science, and Social Studies. The lessons include modifications and accommodations according to individual educational plans, as well as learning extension activities, assuring successful learning to all students.
- Assess student learning and analyze results to guide instruction.
- Create a student-centered environment in the classroom, where children are encouraged to take risks, explore, question, discuss, and problem-solve in order to build knowledge and self-confidence.

## F.A. March Elementary School, Easton Area School District, Easton, PA 2007-2009 Fourth Grade Teacher

- Planned and implemented lessons aligned with PA Standards for Language Arts, Math, Science, and Social Studies, and delivered differentiated instruction according to students' needs and strengths.
- Adjusted instruction based on assessment results and expected learning outcomes.

## Hildebrandt Learning Centers of Masonic Village of Elizabethtown, Elizabethtown, PA 2002-2005 Preschool Lead Teacher

- Supervised preschool-age children according to their individual emotional and physical needs by creating a safe and nurturing environment.
- Planned and implemented age-appropriate daily lessons and activities in literature, math, science, social studies, art, gross and fine-motor skills, according to the children's themes of interest.

## Lisbon Area School District, Lisbon 1998-2000

Positive Behavior Support Teacher

- Contributed to the design and implementation of a new PBS system in two K-4 elementary schools.
- Planned and executed weekly lessons on modeling, practicing, and rewarding positive behaviors in the elementary school setting.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Education in Special Education 2005-2009

East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvania, East Stroudsburg, PA GPA 3.85

Bachelor of Arts and Post-baccalaureate Study in Graphic Design
College of Fine Arts of University of Lisbon, Lisbon, Portugal
GPA 3.75

## SKILLS

I am fluent in Portuguese (native language), and proficient in conversational Spanish and Italian. I also have special technological skills which include proficiency in Word/Pages, Excel/Numbers, PowerPoint/Keynote, iMovie, iPhoto, Photoshop, and web design. I apply my previous graphic design education and professional experience to create illustrations for children's books and other child-oriented materials.

## ACTIVITIES

- EASD Math Curriculum Committee member
- EASD Coordinator of the enrichment program Odyssey of the Mind (www.odysseyofthemind.com)
- Co-coordinator of the annual Science Fair and Egg Drop in the school
- Coordinator of the 4-H Incubation and Embryology annual project in second grade
- Coordinator of the following community service activities: Highmark Walk for a Healthy Community,
   Family Connection of Easton 15th Anniversary Art Contest, and March Book Donation Project
- Director of the Children's Art Studio summer camp
- Coordinator of local art contest for 2011 World Children's Festival promoted by the International Child Art Foundation in Washington, D.C. (www.icaf.org)
- Currently illustrating a children's chapter book for Steel Pen Publishing (www.steelpenpublishing.com)
- Currently working on becoming certified in Art Education